UBCMol revisions

resources:
http://chemapps.stolaf.edu/jmol/docs/
www.rcsb.org/pdb/
http://proteopedia.org/wiki/index.php/Main_Page
http://mcdb-webarchive.mcdb.ucsb.edu/sears/biochemistry/info/scriptguide.htm

**************************************
BUGS IN CURRENT IMPLEMENTATION:
color picking acts strangely
script insertion cursor jumps around
load/save (and save JPEG) sometimes target a weird default directory, or doesn't remember your last chosen directory
picking text area doesnt auto scroll to bottom
SELECT column in picking isn't working properly

**************************************

Colors tab:
- add "label" as a checkbox option, to issue the command "color labels <color>"
- move the Rasmol Colours buttons into the Color Tab, under a heading called "Color Schemes"
- include "charge" as a button for a color scheme (along with "cpk" "group" "amino" "chain" etc)


new selection modes:
select by atom number
select by residue number (example: select ASP56;)
select by chain (select by letter, make a button appear for each chain that exists)
select by alphanumeric code (e.g. R46) (Find all amino acid one letter codes and have it translate them to the three letter codes. H=HIS, etc.)
select using a within command


new functionalilty:
expand/resize the display / view window
view/search the pdb text file, copy from it
retain all right-click Jmol menu access in the display window


new commands:
zoom (with number select or a slider?)
set antialiasdisplay on/off
sensible menu items:
- File open
- File save as
- Save as image formats other than jpeg
Help?

scripts:
clear button
drag/drop scripts into the script window
undo/redo in script window
needs a right click menu for open, save, saveas, copy cut paste
is it possible to create the means to store a list of "favourite" scripts, name them, and assign them hot buttons? 


Add newest version of JMol

A thought:
Could it be possible to run UBCMol remotely through a webpage?



Another python based program: Chimera
Look at Blue Obelisk
DIY Molecules -- useful?
bestchoice.net.nz


################################################
Things I've added so far:

new respresentations:
meshribbon
trace
rockets

Atoms tab, under "Other Sets":
carbohydrate
spine

Under residues tab, add "nucleotides" column
A
C
G
I
T
U
DA
DC
DG
DI
DT
DU

Residues tab, under "select", add
dna
nucleic
purine
pyrimidine
rna

Picking Tab:

Currently, selecting Picking,Center/Identity/Label/etc displays "Set picking xxxx:" in the picking window, but it doesn't tell you what you're supposed to do next.

The following messages should be displayed instead:
Center: "Select an atom about which to center structure position and rotation."
Identify: "Select an atom to identify it."
Label: "Select an atom to display an atom label."
Distance: "Select two atoms to measure the distance between them."
Angle: "Select three atoms sequentially to measure the angle among them."
Torsion: "Select four atoms sequentially to measure the torsion angle among them."
Monitor: "Select two atoms to measure and display the distance between them."

When's all this due? September 2nd